[Road to Success]
[찬여번성: 별처럼 빛나리]
[Episode 3]
[제3화]
How did you defend it?
어떻게 수비해?
-How are you holding up? -Where were you?
- 할 수 있겠어? - 어디 갔어?
Here.
받아
Have some water.
물 좀 마셔
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
네, 선생님
Good job, everyone.
다들 고생 많았어
Do you want to
다들
share your thoughts?
느낀 점 하나씩 얘기해 볼까?
I'll go first.
나 먼저 할게
-Idiot referee! -Wait! Are you out of your mind?
- 무능한 심판 - 왜 그러세요?
You missed your chance.
코치님은 기회 날아갔어요
Next.
다음
I really didn't realize
아까 정말 공이 손에
my hand had touched the ball.
닿은 줄도 몰랐어요
You didn't touch it at all.
닿지도 않았으니까요
That referee is blind.
심판이 눈 감은 거죠
It was a borderline call.
아까는 파울일 수도 있고 아닐 수도 있는 상황이었는데
Why give them a penalty?
왜 상대한테만 페널티킥을 준 건지 모르겠어요
Forget it.
됐어, 그만해
They always call it against small teams like us.
늘 우리 같은 약팀한테 불리하게 판정하는 법이야
I told you.
내가 진즉 말했잖아
We shouldn't have come here just to get humiliated.
괜히 와서 창피 당하지 말자고
Ms. Lin,
선생님
who is this guy next to you?
옆에 계신 분은 누구세요?
I forgot to introduce him.
너희한테 소개하는 걸 깜빡했다
He's my primary school classmate
여기는 내 초등학교 동창이고
who just came back from abroad.
얼마 전에 외국에서 돌아온
He's a professional football coach.
전문 축구 코치야
Make your lies somewhat logical.
거짓말하시려면 좀 논리적으로 하세요
Do you know how hard it is to get a coaching license abroad?
외국 코치 라이센스 따는 게 얼마나 어려운지 아시잖아요
Miss, he's trying to hit on you, right?
선생님한테 작업 거는 거 아니에요?
Don't call him out.
알아도 모르는 척해
Yes.
맞아
-He's not even pretending anymore. -What did I say?
- 당당하게 나오시네 - 내가 뭐랬어?
I mean
내 말은
getting a football coaching license abroad
외국 축구 코치 라이센스
is indeed difficult.
따기 어렵다는 뜻이었어
Why would a professional football coach
외국에서 돌아온 전문 축구 코치님이
who just came back from abroad
왜 저희 같은
come to watch our school football game?
학교 축구 경기를 보러 오신 거예요?
Don't you find it boring?
지루하지 않으세요?
Yeah.
맞아요
Not at all.
지루하지 않아
I think every football match
난 모든 축구 경기가
is very interesting.
다 재미있다고 생각해
Any other questions?
또 질문 있어?
If you are a coach,
코치님이라면
are you the kind who coaches kids?
유소년 애들 축구 가르치는 그런 코치님이세요?
I used to coach a youth team.
예전에 유소년 팀을 맡았었는데
Now I'm unemployed.
지금은 귀국해서 쉬고 있어
Youth team?
유소년 팀?
Which lousy club?
몇 부 리그 클럽인데요?
Nanton.
사우샘프턴
Impossible.
말도 안 돼
Do you know
사우샘프턴 유소년 팀이
where Nanton Youth Team stands in Europe?
유럽에서 어느 정도 수준인지나 아세요?
Well then,
그럼
tell me.
대답해 보세요
Last year in the European Youth League,
작년 유럽 유소년 리그
how many points did Nanton get
사우샘프턴이 첫 시즌 1라운드에서
in the first stage of the first season?
승점을 몇 점 얻었고
What was their ranking?
몇 등인지요
Do you know?
넌 알아?
Can't I test him?
그냥 테스트해 보는 거야
First place.
1등이야
First stage,
1라운드는
8 matches,
8경기고
20 points.
승점 20점을 얻었어
Then who did they play in the last match and what was the score?
그럼 마지막 경기는 누구랑 몇 대 몇이었죠?
If you're so good,
그렇게 대단하신 분이
why did you come back?
귀국은 왜 하셨대?
I don't mind
내가 경기를
telling you stories for the whole second half.
너희한테 하나하나 얘기해 줘도 상관없는데
But my primary school classmate
내 초등학생 동창이
might mind.
싫어할 수도 있을 거 같아
That's right.
맞아
I asked him here
내가 모셔온 건
to teach you guys
너희한테 몇 가지 후반전 축구 전술에 대한
some football tactics for the second half.
코칭이 필요해서야
Isn't this just a formality?
그냥 형식적으로 풀어나갈 텐데
Do we really need tactics?
무슨 전술이 필요해요?
Right.
맞아요
Our problem right now is,
지금 시급한 문제는
firstly, our stamina may not hold up.
공을 따라가지도 못하는 체력이에요
Secondly,
사기도
our morale is low,
많이 떨어졌고요
and their attack is really strong.
상대 팀 공격이 너무 날카로워서
We probably won't be able to hold them off in the second half.
후반전에는 못 막을 가능성이 큰데
Do you have any suggestions?
해 주실 수 있는 조언이 있을까요?
Your opponent, Ning'an,
상대 팀 닝안은
is nicknamed the Cheetah.
치타라는 별명처럼
As the name implies,
말 그대로
they are fast,
스피드가 빨라
but they also have a weakness.
하지만 약점도 있어
Who doesn't know that?
그걸 누가 몰라요?
They have weak endurance.
지구력이 약하잖아요
Right.
맞아
But your endurance is even worse.
너희는 더 약하지
You guys haven't trained in a long time, right?
너희 오래 쉬었지?
Qin Ao.
친아오
Any suggestions?
방법이 있을까요?
If you want to win,
이기고 싶으면
just listen to me.
내 말대로 해
It feels like he's speaking in professional terms.
저렇게 전문 용어들을
But when he puts them all together,
막상 다 늘어놓으니까
I can't understand a thing.
하나도 못 알아듣겠네
This guy
이 사람
is really weird.
진짜 이상하다
Why did he suddenly appear at my house,
왜 갑자기 우리 집에 나타나고
and then suddenly appear here?
또 갑자기 여기에 나타난 거지?
Is it really
정말
just a coincidence?
그냥 우연일까?
Never mind.
모르겠다
I'll focus on the match first.
일단 경기부터 하자
Those who want to hear the tactics,
전술 들을 사람
come here.
이리 와
Lin Lu, hurry.
린루, 빨리
-Come here, everyone. -Let's just listen.
- 다들 이리 와 - 들어 보자
There's no harm anyway.
나쁠 건 없잖아
Let's go.
가자
Fu.
푸신수
Come on, defenders, raise your hands.
수비수 손 들어 봐
You three start from here.
너희 셋은 여기서
Although the curling shots...
아웃프런트 킥이
I'm so sleepy.
졸리다
Are a bit hard for you now.
좀 어렵긴 하지만
I hope this QR Code is reliable
제발 이 사람이라도
and can actually be useful.
효과가 있었으면 좋겠다
Of course.
물론
If the forwards are making a run in the same direction,
만약 같은 방향의 공격수라면
a driven pass will do.
낮고 빠른 패스를 하면 돼
That simple?
그렇게 간단하다고요?
Wouldn't that be easy to defend against?
그럼 너무 쉽게 막히잖아요
In football,
축구에선
there are many complex tactics,
여러 복잡한 전술들도 있지만
but there is only one
가장 간단한 건
that is the simplest.
딱 하나뿐이야
Which one?
어떤 건데요?
Always stay focused.
항상 집중하는 거지
Your focus should always
심장은 언제나
be on the ball.
공을 향해 뛰니까
Elevating tactics to a philosophical level—
전술을 철학의 경지로 끌어올리셨네
he sure can talk.
말 한 번 거창하다
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
be careful not to get tricked.
사기당하시면 안 돼요
I'm also worried.
나도 걱정된다
You're going to lose anyway.
어차피 질 거
Why not give it a try?
한번 해 보고 져도 되잖아
That makes sense.
그것도 맞네
We're here to have fun anyway.
다들 놀러 온 거니까
Just be happy.
즐거우면 된 거야
Come on!
- 파이팅
[Yongchuan Provincial Youth Super League]
[융촨 유소년 슈퍼리그]
-Come on!
- 움직이자 - 움직여
[Hongjing No. 8 High School vs. Ning'an Experimental School]
- 파이팅
Do you want to try
그 방법
that method?
진짜 해 볼까?
What are you thinking?
그냥 꿈 깨
It's impossible for a Chinese person
중국인은 절대
to coach a European football club.
유럽 축구 클럽 감독이 될 수 없어
If what he said is true,
저 사람 말이 진짜면
I could play in one of Europe's top five leagues.
나도 5대 리그에서 뛰겠다
He's a fraud.
저 사람은 그냥 사기꾼이야
The second half begins.
후반전 경기가 시작됐습니다
The teams switch sides.
양 팀 진영을 바꿔 다시 경기를 펼치겠습니다
Ning'an Experimental School is still in the lead.
닝안 고등학교는 여전히 2 대 0으로
2-0.
앞서 있습니다
Ning'an Experimental School still
닝안 고등학교는 여전히
still leads 2-0.
2 대 0으로 앞서고 있습니다
Hongjing No. 8 High School's attack
훙징 제8고가 드리블 중에
is intercepted again.
다시 턴오버가 나오며
Counterattack!
역습을 시작했습니다
Ning'an Experimental School breaks into the penalty area—
닝안이 페널티 에어리어까지 돌파한 후
a shot from a tight angle!
좁은 각도에서 슛을 날립니다
Feng Suo!
펑쒀 선수가
He saved the ball!
상대방의 슈팅을 막아냅니다
They all say your method is unreliable.
다들 당신 방법이 별로라고 하던데
Will it work?
괜찮을까요?
Indeed.
맞아요
A normal coach
보통 감독들은
wouldn't set it up this way.
그렇게 지시하지 않지만
But I'm no normal coach.
전 아니거든요
How would a normal coach set it up then?
그럼 보통 감독들은 다 어떻게 지시하는데요?
They would have them play mid-block defense first,
일단 미드필더가 수비하게 해서
draw the opponent's attack,
상대 공격을 유도한 다음
and then launch a counterattack.
수비 후에 역습을 하죠
Then why didn't you?
그럼 왜 그렇게 안 했어요?
We're already behind anyway.
어차피 이미 뒤지고 있는데
We might as well go all out.
한번 부딪혀 보는 거죠
More importantly,
중요한 건
I can't let your money go to waste.
당신 돈을 헛되이 쓸 순 없잖아요
After all, I'm worth it.
내가 비싼 몸이거든요
Boss, I really can't run anymore.
대장, 나 진짜 못 뛰겠어
I feel like I'll drop dead if I keep running.
더 뛰면 돌연사할 것 같아
Slow down. Don't get hurt.
그럼 다치지 않게
Take it easy.
살살해
Alright.
알았어
Why is the opponent obviously exhausted
분명 상대도 체력이 바닥났을 텐데
but still trying so hard?
왜 저렇게 열심히 뛰죠?
Because you are too weak,
우리 팀이 약하니까
and they want to score more goals.
골을 더 넣고 싶은 거죠
So cunning.
되게 영악하네요
The goalkeeper of Hongjing No. 8 High School
훙징 제8고의 골키퍼가
throws the ball to No. 6 Lin Lu.
손으로 6번 린루에게 공을 던져줍니다
Lin Lu passes to No. 10 Fu Xinshu.
린루가 10번 푸신수에게 공을 패스합니다
Try a long pass from the backfield
후방에서 롱패스를 시도해서
to find the forward.
공격수를 찾는 거야
Just rely on the forward's precise first touch.
공격수의 정확한 패스 컨트롤에 의존하는 거지
Qin Ao, Chen Jianghe!
친아오, 천장허
-Let's try it. -A long pass!
- 해 보자 - 롱패스입니다
It's actually a long pass tactic!
갑자기 롱패스 전술입니다
The pass goes over Ning'an Experimental School's defense line
패스가 닝안의 수비 라인을 넘어서
and reaches the forward!
공격수에게 전달됩니다
Qin Ao!
친아오
They're very fast!
움직임이 빠릅니다
This ball is passed to Chen Jianghe!
공이 천장허에게
Chen Jianghe shoots!
천장허, 슛
What a pity. The shot is blocked.
아쉽게도 공이 막힙니다
Although it didn't go in,
골은 안 들어갔지만
this is the first time
훙징 제8고가 처음으로
we've seen effective teamwork from
유효 슛을 날립니다
-Hongjing No. 8 High School, come on! -Hongjing No. 8 High School! What happened just now?
- 훙징 제8고 파이팅 - 약속된 플레이군요
Their form
선수들의 컨디션이
has obviously improved.
확실히 좋아졌습니다
It's impossible for a Chinese person to coach
중국인은 절대
a European football club.
유럽 축구 클럽 감독이 될 수 없어
Wide.
빗나가네
If what he said is true,
저 사람 말이 진짜면
I could play in one of Europe's top five leagues.
나도 5대 리그에서 뛰겠다
Too high.
뜬다
It's over.
막히네
It's a mess.
엉망이야
Can you stop talking?
조용히 좀 해 줄래요?
[78']
[경기 시간 78분째]
It's the 78th minute of the match.
경기는 78분째로 접어들었습니다
Hongjing No. 8 High School has a corner kick,
훙징 제8고의 코너킥 기회입니다
taken by No. 6, Lin Lu.
6번 린루 선수가 차겠습니다
The ball is passed to No. 9, Qin Ao.
9번 친아오에게 패스합니다
Qin Ao fails to win the header.
친아오의 헤딩 경합이 실패합니다
Hongjing No. 8 High School
훙징 제8고는 헤딩 경합에서
no longer has the advantage in the air.
우위를 점하지 못하고 있습니다
Possession goes to Ning'an Experimental School.
공은 닝안 쪽으로 넘어갔습니다
No. 14 and No. 13
14번과 13번 선수가
[Yongchuan Provincial Youth Super League]
[융촨 유소년 슈퍼리그]
are linking up.
패스를 주고받습니다
[Hongjing No. 8 High School vs. Ning'an Experimental School]
[훙징 제8고등학교 닝안 실험고등학교]
And shoot!
슛
The ball is saved by Hongjing No. 8 High School's goalkeeper.
이 공은 훙징 제8고 골키퍼가 막아냅니다
Their players are better built than our forwards.
상대 피지컬이 우리 공격수보다 좋아서
So normally,
합리적인 상황에서도
when you fight for the ball,
공을 뺏으러 가면
you have no advantage.
유리할 게 없어
You need to be flexible and avoid direct confrontation.
정면충돌은 요령껏 피해야 해
Don't rely on your height in aerial duels.
키 크다고 제공권만 노리지 말고
Keep your eyes on the landing point
세컨 볼을 노려
and compete for the second ball.
세컨 볼에서 볼 소유권을 가져오는 거야
We can see Qin Ao from Hongjing No. 8 High School
훙징 제8고의 친아오 선수가 보입니다
no longer going for aerial duels like before,
이전처럼 제공권을 노리지 않고
but instead moving to the landing point to compete for the second ball.
세컨 볼을 노리는군요
Let's trust him for now!
일단 한번 믿어 보자
It's a brilliant decision!
절묘한 판단입니다
He successfully intercepts the ball.
공을 성공적으로 가로챕니다
How did Hongjing No. 8 High School suddenly come up with this?
훙징 제8고가 갑자기 각성했습니다
Their new tactic is really impressive!
새로운 전술이 아주 뛰어나네요
It's a goal!
골
-Well done! -Congratulations to Hongjing No. 8 High School for pulling one back!
- 잘했어 - 훙징이 한 골을 만회합니다
The score is now 2-1.
스코어는 2 대 1입니다
[Ning'an Experimental School 2–0 Hongjing No. 8 High School]
[닝안 실험고등학교 02] [훙징 제8고등학교 01]
Qin Ao!
친아오
Nice shot!
잘 찼어
Bro!
그렇지
-The match is almost over. -Well done!
- 이제 마지막이야 - 할 수 있어
-One more! -Let's go! One more goal!
- 한 골 더 넣자 - 한 골만 더
Such a goal is impossible to replicate.
저런 슛은 두 번 다신 못 찰 겁니다
It not only helps them pull one back,
이 골은 한 점을 만회했을 뿐만 아니라
but more importantly,
팀 전체의
it helps the whole team
자신감을 되찾는
regain confidence.
계기가 되었습니다
Keep trying to win possession.
계속해서 볼 소유권을 가져와서
Play long balls up to the forwards.
공격수한테 롱패스해 봐
This QR Code
저 사람
really knows his stuff.
그래도 제법이네
[Yongchuan Provincial Youth Super League]
[융촨 유소년 슈퍼리그]
Three minutes of stoppage time in the second half.
후반전 추가 시간은 3분입니다
[Hongjing No. 8 High School vs. Ning'an Experimental School]
[훙징 제8고등학교 닝안 실험고등학교]
The current score is 2-1.
현재 스코어는 2 대 1
Ning'an Experimental School is in the lead.
닝안 실험고등학교가 앞서 있습니다
Players from both sides are giving it their all.
양 팀 선수들 모두 필사적으로 공을 다투고 있습니다
In the final moments,
마지막 순간
will Hongjing No. 8 High School equalize,
과연 훙징 제8고가 동점을 만들지
or will Ning'an Experimental School win the game?
아니면 닝안이 순조롭게 승리할지 기대됩니다
Fu!
푸신수
Ning'an Experimental School's corner kick—
닝안의 코너킥입니다
let's see who wins the second ball.
낮은 지점에서의 경합을 지켜보시죠
No. 12, Chen Weidong,
12번 천웨이둥 선수가
intercepted the ball.
공을 막아냈습니다
He might be offside!
훙징 제8고가 오프사이드에 걸렸을까요?
All their players
저쪽 선수들이 전부
are too close to our half.
우리 진영에 너무 가까이 붙었어
This forces our forwards
이러면 우리 공격수가
to move back with them.
어쩔 수 없이 뒤로 물러나야 해서
It's easy to fall into an offside trap.
오프사이드에 걸리기 쉬울 거야
Our space is too small.
공간이 너무 좁아
They are setting an offside trap.
쟤들이 오프사이드 트랩을 쓰면
Can't you beat the offside trap?
너희는 그걸 역이용하면 되잖아
Because of your frequent attacks,
너희가 계속 공격하니까
their defenders are reaching their limit.
저쪽 수비수들도 한계에 다다랐을 거야
Especially the right-back.
특히 오른쪽 수비수는
He's slow to turn to his left.
왼쪽으로 도는 속도가 느려서
Play down his left side.
왼쪽으로 제치고
Fall back and defend!
수비 복귀해
They beat the offside trap!
오프사이드를 역이용한 플레이입니다
What an amazing decision!
그야말로 신의 한 수 같은 판단이네요
Would their defenders make such a mistake?
상대 수비수들이 저런 실수를 한다고요?
They completely changed!
완전히 다른 팀이 됐습니다
They're showing why they were once runners-up!
역시 예전 준우승팀답습니다
If you are lucky enough.
운이 좋으면 말이야
A goal!
들어갔습니다
My God! In stoppage time!
세상에나, 추가 시간에 말이죠
We didn't lose!
우리가 안 졌다
It's a last-minute equalizer to make it 2–2!
2 대 2로 극적인 동점을 만들었습니다
Bravo!
잘했어
We didn't lose!
우린 지지 않았어
♪ Who isn't going through nights of darkness and confusion ♪
♪ 누구나 어둠과 방황의 시간을 지나 ♪
♪ Stumbling, covered in wounds, losing direction ♪
♪ 넘어지고 상처투성이가 되며 방향을 잃은 채 ♪
♪ Wandering alone, gaining strength through pain ♪
♪ 홀로 헤매지만 그렇게 강해지는 법이야 ♪
Thank you
고마워요
for helping them turn the tide.
덕분에 지진 않았네요
No need.
됐어요
♪ Riding the wind, chasing an unknown horizon ♪
♪ 바람을 타고 미지의 내일을 향해 달려가 ♪
You paid for it.
돈값 한 거죠
I can see
이제 보니 쟤네도
♪ Looking up, dreaming side by side of great ideals ♪
♪ 고개를 들어 원대한 꿈을 간직한 채 ♪
that they didn't really want to lose.
지기 싫었나 봐요
They were just afraid of losing face.
그냥 창피한 게 싫었을 뿐이지
♪ The vast world awaits youth to arrive ♪
♪ 드넓은 세상에 우린 거침없이 뛰어들 거야 ♪
♪ If braving the wind and waves ♪
♪ 거센 풍파를 용감하게 마주하는 것만이 ♪
♪ Can be called growth ♪
♪ 성장이라고 한다면 ♪
He just left?
가나?
♪ I will stubbornly go against the current ♪
♪ 난 기꺼이 그곳에서 ♪
♪ And run wild once ♪
♪ 뜨겁게 싸워 볼 거야 ♪
How rude.
진짜 매너도 없네
♪ Even if the road ahead is long ♪
♪ 미래가 멀다 해도 ♪
If you don't try your best,
최선을 다하지 않으면
♪ I will still be unstoppable ♪
♪ 내 질주는 멈추지 않아 ♪
luck won't favor you.
운도 따르지 않는 법이죠
♪ Break through all confusion ♪
♪ 모든 방황을 부수며 ♪
♪ Chase my own light ♪
♪ 나만의 빛을 쫓아가 ♪
♪ In the storm I grow resilient wings ♪
♪ 풍파 속에서 끝내 강인한 날개를 펼칠 테니까 ♪
♪ Even if no one is clapping ♪
♪ 모두가 날 외면해도 ♪
-You practiced in secret? -Amazing, right?
- 몰래 연습했지? - 장난 아니지?
♪ I will still fight my way forward ♪
♪ 힘을 다해 싸울 거야 ♪
Just that one shot.
슛 한 방에...
Awesome, bro.
대박이었어
You've definitely been practicing in secret.
몰래 연습한 거지?
Awesome.
완전 미쳤더라
What are you doing?
왜?
You must be Ms. Lin from the P.E. department.
체육부 린 선생님 맞으시죠?
I'm Director Jin.
저는 진 주임입니다
The chemistry competition just ended.
화학 경시대회가 방금 끝났는데
Their bus happens to be broken.
마침 차가 고장 나서요
They have to rush back for a post-competition review.
빨리 돌아가서 경기 복기를 해야 하거든요
Let us borrow your bus.
차 좀 빌려 쓸게요
Director Jin, this is our football team's car.
진 주임님 이건 저희 축구팀 차인데
If your car is broken,
차가 고장 나셨으면
how about we squeeze in together?
다 같이 좀 끼여서 가면 어떨까요?
But...
근데
There are only so many seats.
자리가 얼마 없어서
I'm afraid we won't fit.
다 못 탈 것 같은데요?
The academic teachers are still waiting
과목 선생님들께서 아직 학교에서
at school.
기다리고 계세요
You guys on the team, please do me a favor.
축구팀 학생들, 좀 부탁할게
Thank you.
고맙다
I'll have the bus come back to pick you up later.
차는 이따가 다시 와서 너희 태우라고 할게
Aren't we in a hurry too?
자기들만 급하고 우린 뭐 한가한 줄 아나?
Mr. Jin is the most biased teacher.
진 주임님은 유독 이기적이라니까
We're all tired after the match too.
우리도 방금 경기 끝나서 힘들어 죽겠는데
He didn't even pretend to care.
이제 대놓고 저러네
He kicked the ladder away after climbing up.
아예 토사구팽하는 거 아냐?
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
what should we do?
저희 이제 어떡해요?
I don't know.
나도 모르겠어
I'm new here too.
나도 새로 왔거든
How about
아니면
I treat you to something nice to eat?
내가 맛있는 거 사 줄까?
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
I know a really good stir-fry restaurant nearby.
이 근처에 진짜 맛있는 볶음 요리집 알아요
But... it's a bit expensive.
가격이 좀 비싸긴 하지만
It doesn't matter.
괜찮아
As long as you're happy.
너희만 좋으면 됐지
Where is it?
어딘데?
Over there.
저쪽이요
Let's go.
가자
-Let's go.
- 가자 - 가
How did you get in?
어떻게 들어왔어?
The door downstairs was wide open.
아래층 문이 열려 있던데?
And your own door was unlocked.
너 문 안 잠갔더라
Stop looking so miserable.
인상 좀 펴
Look what I brought you.
내가 뭐 가져왔는지 봐
Doesn't it make the place feel more alive?
사람 사는 집 같지 않아?
It's okay.
그럴싸하네
Store them yourself.
알아서 정리해
Just okay?
그럴싸하긴
How would you survive without me?
나 없으면 어떻게 살래?
Wi-Fi, Wi-Fi, Wi-Fi.
와이파이, 와이파이
Wang Fa.
왕파
Why
왜 공유기 뒤에
isn't the password on the back of the router?
비밀번호를 안 적어 놨어?
The password is 8 eights.
비밀번호는 숫자 8 여덟 개야
Internet isn't that expensive.
인터넷 요금이 저렴하더라고
Eight eights?
8이 여덟 개라고?
Change it.
좀 바꿔라
That's too easy to guess.
너무 뻔하잖아
Anyone can connect.
아무나 다 쓰겠다
Alright, connected.
됐다, 연결됐어
Sharing the same network makes us family.
같은 인터넷을 써야 한 가족이지
Who's your family?
누가 너랑 한 가족이래?
Did my sister say yes to you?
우리 누나가 허락했어?
Watch your mouth.
얘 말하는 것 좀 봐
Once I, Yu Bo, am your agent,
나 위보는 네 매니저야
I'm your agent for life.
평생 매니저란 말이야
Of course we're family.
당연히 한 가족이지
Your new house is...
새집인데...
Who's calling at this hour?
이 시간에 누가 전화하는 거야?
Hello?
여보세요
How did the interview go?
면접 결과는 어떻게 됐어요?
Really?
네, 정말요?
That's great.
잘됐네요
Yes.
네, 맞아요
I also think I'm indeed
저도 제가 정말
the best fit for Yongchuan Hengjiu.
융촨에서 가장 적합한 인재라고 생각해요
Okay.
네
I got it.
알겠습니다
Bye.
끊을게요
Yes! Yes! Yes!
아싸!
My lifelong agent
내 평생의 매니저가
is running away now?
이제 튀려는 거야?
I'm going to Yongchuan Hengjiu.
내가 갈 곳은 융촨이야
Yongchuan is the closest place to your sister.
융촨이 네 누나랑 제일 가까운 곳이잖아
Let me borrow a suit of yours.
정장 한 벌만 빌려 줘
I need to look the part.
마침 폼 좀 잡아야 하거든
[Studied in the UK] [Psychology major]
[영국 유학생 심리학 전공]
[Likes spicy food] [Hates coriander]
[매운 걸 좋아하고 고수를 싫어한다]
[Not good at sports] [Can't ride a bike] [Hates rainy days]
[자전거를 탈 줄 모른다] [비 오는 날을 싫어한다]
[Spade Q, Lin Wanxing]
[스페이드 Q, 린완싱]
Did you come all the way to Hongjing
설마 일부러 훙징까지 와서
just to investigate Lin Wanxing?
린완싱을 조사하려는 건 아니지?
Yes.
맞아
Lin Wanxing
린완싱은
is my landlady now.
지금 내 집주인이야
She lives downstairs.
바로 아래층에 살고
Okay.
그래
-This hits the spot. -7, 8, 9, 10, 11.
- 역시 이 맛이지 - 일곱, 여덟, 아홉...
Nothing like an iced tea after a match.
경기 끝나고 마시는 아이스티가 최고라니까
If we hadn't run into Jin Laoyao today,
오늘 진 주임만 안 만났어도
it would've been perfect.
진짜 완벽했을 텐데
It's not the first time we've been despised.
어차피 무시당한 게 한두 번도 아니고
Aren't you used to it by now?
아직도 적응 안 됐냐?
True.
하긴
A lousy football team
축구나 하는 별 볼 일 없는 팀이니까
means nothing.
아무것도 아니지
Guys,
얘들아
don't come to me for this kind of thing again.
앞으로 이런 일엔 나 부르지 마
It's too annoying.
진짜 짜증 나거든
Don't say that.
그렇게 말하지 마
We got our special admission spots
우리 특기생 정원도
because we played football.
축구 때문에 받은 거잖아
Yeah.
맞아
Even though we only came in second place
중학교 때 지역 결승전에서
in the junior high regional finals,
준우승밖에 못 했지만
didn't Jiang still let us get special admission
그래도 장 선생님이 우리를 특기생으로
to Hongjing No. 8 High School?
훙징 제8고에 넣어 주셨잖아
Back then, we were all in one talent class.
그때 다 같이 특기반에 들어가서
That was great.
얼마나 좋았는데
So what?
그래서 뭐?
Didn't he abandon us in the end?
결국엔 우리를 버렸잖아
Exactly.
맞아
When the talent class was disbanded,
특기반이 해체할 때
did anyone ask for our opinion?
누가 우리 의견을 물어보기라도 했어?
We made a fuss at the Academic Affairs Office with Qin,
우리가 진 주임이랑 교무처 가서 따졌다가
and almost got a demerit, right?
벌점 받을 뻔했잖아
We all ended up as transfer students
결국 다 전학생 신세가 돼서
and were looked down on wherever we went.
여기저기서 무시나 당하고
Don't tell me you've all forgotten.
이것까지 잊었다고 하지 마
And that Jiang Tianyu.
그리고 그 장톈위
If he hadn't left,
걔만 안 갔어도
would we have been disbanded in our freshman year?
우리 팀이 고1 때 해체됐을까?
How many orders of salted egg yolk chicken wings do you want?
단황 치킨 윙은 몇 인분 시킬까?
Are 2 enough?
2인분이면 돼?
That's not enough.
2인분으로 되겠어요?
We need at least 4.
최소 4인분은 시켜야죠
You guys order.
너희가 시켜라
I'm telling you.
얘들아, 내가 시킬게
I want the shredded potatoes.
난 감자채 볶음
-I want bullfrog. -And braised pork.
- 난 황소개구리... - 동파육
You're too slow.
꾸물거리지 말고
Give it to me. Give it to me.
그냥 나 줘
Too slow.
답답해 죽겠네
Do you want braised pork?
동파육 시킬까?
Yes, two orders.
- 시켜 - 2인분 시키자
-Stir-fried beef. -You guys keep ordering.
- 소고기 볶음은? - 너희가 계속 시켜
Three orders.
3인분 시켜
Just order 2.
2인분만 시켜
-Duck claws. -Let's get more. 3 orders.
- 오리발은? - 그건 많이 시켜, 3인분
Spicy soft-shelled turtle.
매운 자라 볶음은?
Yes.
시켜, 시켜
Cabbage...
양배추 볶음은
Since there are so many of us, get 3 orders.
사람도 많은데 3인분 시키자
Sure.
그래, 좋아
Ms. Lin, what do you want to eat?
린 선생님은 뭐 드시고 싶으세요?
Let me see.
어디 좀 보자
Okay.
네
By the way, Ms. Lin,
참, 린 선생님
we won today all thanks to your elementary school classmate.
오늘 저희가 이긴 거 다 선생님의 동창 덕분인데
Why didn't you invite him to eat with us?
왜 같이 회식하자고 안 하셨어요?
It was just a chance encounter. No need for that.
우연히 만났는데 그럴 필요까지 있겠어?
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
he said he was the former coach of Nanton.
자기가 예전에 사우샘프턴 감독이었다는데
Is that true?
진짜는 아니죠?
Bro,
야
if he's the former Nanton coach,
그 사람이 사우샘프턴 감독이었으면
I'm Mbappé.
난 음바페다
Then I'm Yamal.
그럼 난 야말
If you don't believe me, I'll check right now
못 믿겠으면 내가 지금 그 사기꾼의
and expose this liar.
정체를 밝혀 줄게
[Winfred Wang] [Nanton Fan Forum]
[윈프레드 왕 사우샘프턴 팬 커뮤니티]
[Winfred Wang]
[윈프레드 왕]
Oh my. Come on.
대박이다 다들 이리 와 봐
Wait. Is it really him?
진짜 그 사람이네
-What? -Mr. Win.
- 아니... - 윈 감독이다
Is it really him?
진짜야?
-It's really him. -It's really him?
- 진짜라니까 - 진짜라고?
-I remember him. -Is it really him?
- 어디서 본 거 같은데 - 진짜였어?
Mr. Win.
윈 감독이라고?
-Hello, excuse me. The food is here. -The food is here.
- 잠시만요, 음식 나왔습니다 - 죄송합니다, 음식 나왔대
-Who cares which team he coaches? -It's really him.
- 어느 팀 감독이든 상관없어 - 진짜였네
I'm hungry anyway.
지금은 배고프니까
I'll eat first.
나 먼저 먹을게
Here, Ms. Lin.
린 선생님도 드세요
Thank you.
고마워
By the way, Fu,
참, 푸신수
the thing you mentioned before—
네가 전에 말했던 거 있잖아
the weird thing you received—
네가 받았다는 그 이상한 물건
should you tell me what it is now?
이제 좀 말해 줘
There's nothing.
아니야
What?
뭐?
I didn't receive anything.
나 아무것도 받은 거 없어
I lied.
내가 거짓말한 거야
I just wanted us to play football together.
난 그냥 다 같이 축구하고 싶었을 뿐이야
Fu,
푸신수
you really want to play football that much?
그렇게 축구가 하고 싶었어?
What was there to look forward to
어차피 질 경기인데
in a game we were bound to lose?
뭘 그렇게 기대해?
Was it necessary for you to do this?
이렇게까지 할 필요가 있어?
It's fine.
괜찮아
Just treat it as a free autumn trip.
공짜로 가을 소풍 왔다 치면 되지
And we got a free meal out of it, right?
게다가 공짜 밥도 얻어먹었잖아, 안 그래?
Yeah, that's right.
맞아
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
- 린 선생님, 감사합니다
By the way,
근데 말이야
this game is a draw.
이번 경기는 비겼으니까
Are we going to keep playing?
우리 계속해야 하는 거 아냐?
Keep playing?
뭘 또 해?
Why bother?
뭘 하냐고?
They dribbled past us like we weren't even there.
길바닥 신세나 다름없는데 무슨 축구를 해?
Have some awareness, bro.
분수 좀 알자, 친구야
We're just a bunch of losers.
우린 그냥 찌질이들이라
We should just hide in the corner.
구석에나 찌그러져 있어야 하는 거야
Why dream of shining?
무슨 빛을 보겠다고 난리야?
Anyway,
어쨌든
we accomplished our mission honorably.
우리도 영광스럽게 임무를 완수한 셈이니까
It's good to quit while we're ahead,
이쯤에서 그만두는 것도 괜찮은데
isn't it?
안 그래?
Yeah, we don't even have a full team.
맞아요 어차피 스쿼드도 부족하잖아요
Come on.
잔 들어
To our honorable retirement.
우리의 영광스러운 은퇴를 위하여
-Come on. -Cheers to losers.
- 잔 들어 - 찌질이들을 위해 건배
-Cheers!
- 건배
This is really delicious.
이거 진짜 맛있다
It's really delicious.
맛있지?
You eat this.
너 이거 먹어
I want to eat that.
난 저거 먹을래
I want to eat this.
난 이거 먹을래
This one is a bit salty.
이건 좀 짜다
-This is quite good. -This is not bad.
- 이거 괜찮네 - 맛있다
I'm so full.
배불러
Really stuffed.
진짜 배 터지겠다
Thank you, Ms. Lin, for treating us to this meal.
린 선생님 식사 대접해 주셔서 감사합니다
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
- 린 선생님, 감사합니다
You're welcome.
아니야
Do you really like playing football?
축구가 그렇게 좋니?
Then why don't you look happy?
근데 왜 별로 안 기뻐하는 거야?
Isn't today's result quite good?
오늘 경기 괜찮았잖아
I am happy.
기뻐요
Just too happy.
너무 기뻐서 그래요
Originally, I thought
원래는
we'd play one more game with them,
쟤들이랑 한 번 더 경기하고
just to satisfy our craving,
실컷 즐기면 그만이라고 생각했어요
since we were bound to lose anyway.
어차피 질 게 뻔하니까요
I really thought it was the last game.
정말 마지막 경기라고 생각했거든요
If we lost, everyone would give up.
여기서 지면 다들 미련을 버릴 테니까요
But...
하지만...
You want to continue?
계속하고 싶었구나
Ms. Lin, do you think I'm
선생님, 제가
biting off more than I can chew?
너무 분수를 모른다고 생각하시죠?
How could I?
무슨 소리야?
If you were really that bad at football,
정말 실력이 없었다면
you wouldn't have been admitted
너희는
as sports recruits.
체육 특기생으로 입학하지도 못했을 거야
The talent class has been disbanded.
특기반도 해체됐는데
What kind of sports recruits are we now?
저희가 무슨 특기생이에요?
Actually, today,
사실 오늘
drawing with them
걔네랑 비긴 것만 해도
really feels like a dream.
정말 꿈만 같았어요
I really love football.
저는 축구를 정말 좋아해요
So I don't want it to end.
그래서 끝내고 싶지 않아요
I know better than anyone else
물론 누구보다 잘 알고 있어요
that we are already in high school.
저희도 이제 고등학생이잖아요
Those who have what it takes would have shown it by now.
될 놈은 진작에 됐겠죠
Football is a game of 11 players.
축구는 11명이 하는 경기인데
It's impossible for everyone to be willing
모두가 저처럼 열의를
to play along with me like this.
가질 리 없겠지만
But I...
저는
just can't bring myself to give up.
이대로 포기할 수 없어요
Ms. Lin,
선생님
in this life,
저는 이번 생에
I don't have any chances left.
더는 기회가 없을 거예요
Fu, stop chatting!
푸신수, 그만 얘기하고
-The bus is here! Let's go! -Let's go, Fu!
- 어서 와, 차 도착했다 - 가자, 푸신수
Coming.
갈게
Go, go, go!
어서 와
Hurry up.
빨리
Coming!
가고 있어
Why did he go to sleep so early?
벌써 자는 건가?
I'll thank him another day.
다음에 고맙다고 해야겠다
Dream?
꿈이라고?
I really love football.
저는 축구를 정말 좋아해요
So I don't want it to end.
그래서 끝내고 싶지 않아요
What does that have to do with me?
나랑 무슨 상관이겠어?
I knew it.
그럴 줄 알았어
Wang Fa?
코치님
Sorry.
미안해요
I saw your door was unlocked, so I let myself in.
문이 안 잠겨 있길래 그냥 들어왔어요
Miss Landlady,
집주인 아가씨가
it's so late.
이렇게 늦은 시간에
Is there something you need?
무슨 일이죠?
Your floor is leaking water.
댁에서 물이 새요
Sorry,
미안해요
I didn't notice.
미처 몰랐네요
It's okay,
괜찮아요
but please get someone to fix it as soon as possible.
번거롭겠지만 사람 불러서 빨리 처리해 주세요
I didn't scare you, did I?
나 때문에 놀란 건 아니죠?
No.
아니에요
Holding your breath underwater
물속에서 숨을 참는 건
must be for seeking inner peace.
마음의 안정을 찾기 위해서잖아요
I suggest you
차라리
try diving. The effect might be better.
잠수를 하는 게 더 효과가 좋을 거예요
It seems you
집주인 아가씨는
know a lot about psychology.
심리학에 대해 잘 아나 봐요?
It's just a friendly reminder.
그냥 좋은 뜻에서 말하는 거예요
After all, I am your landlady.
어쨌든 내가 집주인이니까
If anything really happens to you,
당신한테 무슨 일 생기면
it will be very tricky for me.
나까지 곤란해지거든요
[Administrative Building]
[본관]
Director Qian,
첸 주임님
I've thought about it.
생각해 봤는데요
The football team's draw this time
축구팀이 이번에 비긴 걸 보면
shows they're actually pretty good.
실력이 그렇게 나쁘진 않다는 뜻이에요
What they need is a more professional supervisor.
애들한테 필요한 건 더 전문적인 코치란 거죠
I think...
제 생각엔
the teachers in the P.E. department are very suitable.
체육부 선생님들이 딱 맞는 것 같아요
Director,
주임님
I can't do it.
전 안 돼요
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
the fact that you achieved such a result the first time you led the team
처음 팀을 이끌고 이런 성적을 냈다는 건
means you are very competent
린 선생님이 코치 자리에
-for the position of supervisor. -Here we go ahain.
- 적임자라는 뜻이에요 - 또 시작이네
You must continue to work hard in the future.
앞으로도 계속 수고해 줘요
Director, I really can't do it.
주임님, 전 정말 안 돼요
Actually, in the P.E. department,
사실 체육부의
the other teachers' schedules are very full.
다른 선생님들은 수업이 꽉 차 있어요
Mr. Li, that track and field competition of yours,
리 선생님 그 육상 대회 말인데
is it going to start soon?
곧 시작하지 않아요?
Yes, our track and field team is very busy with training.
맞아요, 저희는 육상부 훈련 때문에 엄청 바빠요
The competition will start next month.
다음 달부터 바로 시합이거든요
Your ball game competition...
농구부는요?
Our basketball group also has a competition next month.
저희 농구부도 다음 달에 시합이에요
Ball games group is also very busy.
농구부도 바쁘네요
I can't do it.
전 안 돼요
I don't know anything.
전 아무것도 못 해요
Look at them.
봤죠?
All of them are actually very busy.
다들 정말 바쁘다잖아요
Alright,
아이고
we are back to square one.
결국 돌고 돌았네
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
you haven't been at the school for long.
학교 온 지 얼마 안 돼서
I have to tell you the truth about some things.
솔직하게 말해 줘야 할 게 있어요
Actually, the competition for positions in the school
사실 학교 내 자리 경쟁이
is very fierce.
생각보다 아주 치열해요
-He's going to use his trump card again. -Especially during the probation period.
- 또 필살기를 꺼내시겠네 - 특히 교생 기간에는
It mainly depends on your performance.
주로 성과를 봐야 하거든요
You see, you are a contract worker,
린 선생님은 계약직이고
and you haven't become a regular employee yet, right?
아직 정규직 전환도 안 됐잖아요
How can you become a regular employee then?
그럼 어떻게 해야 정규직이 될 수 있을까요?
You have to complete...
바로 실적을
-I was too naive. -the task assigned by the school leaders
- 내가 너무 순진했네 - 학교에서 내린 임무들을
and achieve good results.
잘 해내야 하는 거예요
I actually believed that it was just a one-round tour,
예선 탈락으로 끝날 거란 걸
just going through the motions.
그대로 믿었다니
Now it seems that I have to take this job whether I want to or not.
그냥 이 일은 좋든 싫든 해야겠네
That's impossible.
그건 불가능해요
So what counts as achieving good results?
그럼 어떻게 해야 실적을 잘 내는 건데요?
I think
그러니까
you have to make it out of the preliminaries and into the next round.
적어도 예선은 통과해서 다음 라운드로 가는 거죠
The next round?
다음 라운드요?
But...
하지만
they don't even have a coach.
애들은 감독도 없는걸요
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
you are absolutely right.
말 잘했어요
As the team supervisor,
담당 선생으로서
you have the responsibility and obligation
책임과 의무를 다해
to find a coach for the team.
팀에 코치 한 명을 구해 오세요
Me? Find a coach?
제가요?
Hurry up and do it now.
서둘러 처리하세요
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
completing the task assigned to you by the school leadership
학교 윗분들께서 맡긴 임무를 완수하는 건
is a very honorable thing.
아주 영광스러운 일이에요
Where am I supposed to find a coach?
내가 어디서 코치를 구해 와?
Go for it.
파이팅
Director Qian,
첸 주임님
school is over, so I'm leaving now.
수업 끝났으니 먼저 가 보겠습니다
-Okay.
- 그래요 - 네
Bye.
안녕히 계세요
Goodbye, Ms. Lin.
잘 가요, 린 선생님
This is too hard for me.
진짜 힘들어 죽겠네
[The Second General Assembly of the Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team]
[훙징 제8고 축구팀 제2차 전체 대표 대회]
The second general sssembly...
제2차 전체 대표 대회
I'm melting, bro.
야, 더워 죽겠다
I can't stand it anymore.
진짜 못 참겠어
What are we doing?
우리 뭐 하는 거야?
Let's go.
가자, 가자
-It stinks. -Seriously.
- 무슨 냄새 안 나? - 그...
-Why did she call us here? -Who knows?
- 우릴 왜 부르셨대? - 글쎄
Hello, Ms. Lin.
선생님, 안녕하세요
Alright, babies.
자, 우리 아가들
Sit down.
앉으렴
I'm not a baby.
전 애기가 아닌데요
What kind of baby eats 3 meals a day,
어느 집 애기가 한 끼에 다섯 그릇씩
and 5 bowls of rice per meal?
하루 세 끼를 먹어요?
Ms. Lin, please watch your words.
린 선생님 말씀 조심해 주세요
Got it.
알았어
My dear ba-
산전수전
-ttle-tested students.
다 겪은 우리 학생 여러분
Find a place to sit.
아무 데나 앉으렴
You are not a baby.
넌 애기가 아니야
-Sit. -Baby Lin Lu, let's go.
- 앉아 - 린루 아가
[The Second General Assembly of the Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team]
[훙징 제8고 축구팀 제2차 전체 대표 대회]
You should know
내가 왜 불렀는지
why I called you here, right?
대충 알겠지?
We refuse.
저희는 거절할래요
That fast?
벌써?
Won't you...
그래도
consider it?
생각 좀 해 보지?
What's there to consider?
뭘 더 생각해요?
In the school's eyes, we're just a bunch of hooligans.
학교는 저희를 그냥 악동으로 보고
The school doesn't value our football team at all.
우리 축구팀을 신경도 안 쓰는데
Why waste time?
뭐 하러 시간 낭비해요?
A-Actually, it's really rare for us
우리한테 정말 흔치 않은
to have this opportunity.
기회잖아
There's nothing wrong with continuing to play,
다시 한번 해 보는 것도 나쁘지 않아
is there?
안 그래?
Fine, let's give it a try.
좋아, 그럼 한번 해 보자
What if they abandon us again
만약에 몇 번 하다가 또 저희를 차 버리면
after a couple of games?
어떡해요?
This time, the school
이번에는 학교에서
really wants to rebuild the team
진짜로 팀을 재건해서
and win back the title of Football Characteristic Campus.
축구 특성화 학교 현판을 되찾고 싶어 해
That's a bit too ambitious.
너무 멀리 가신 거 아니에요?
Yeah, Ms. Lin.
맞아요, 선생님
We were just lucky last time
지난번엔 저희가 운이 좋아서
to tie with Ning'an Experimental School.
닝안과 비긴 건데
And the school wants us to rebuild the
학교에서 뭘 재건한다는 거예요?
Football Characteristic Campus?
축구 특성화 학교요?
I think this task
그건 저희한테
is too heavy for us.
너무 벅찬 일이에요
Besides, we don't even have a coach.
게다가 저희는 감독도 없잖아요
We are trying hard to find a coach already.
감독은 열심히 찾고 있어
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
I'm wondering,
생각해 봤는데
is it possible for us
저희가
to hire a top-level coach?
수준 높은 대단한 감독님을 모셔올 수 있을까요?
Like your elementary school classmate.
예를 들면 선생님 초등학교 동창이요
-Yeah. -Yes.
- 맞아
I think that will work.
좋은 생각이다
With a former Nanton coach leading us,
전 사우샘프턴 감독이 있으면
our team would actually have a chance.
우리 팀도 희망이 생길 거예요
He's really got some skills.
그분 진짜 실력 있잖아요
But...
근데
can we actually invite him over?
저희가 그분을 모셔올 수 있을까요?
That's Nanton, bro.
사우샘프턴 출신이야
How is that possible?
말이 되냐?
Is it really impossible?
정말 안 돼요?
Maybe Ms. Lin isn't capable enough.
린 선생님이 능력이 없나 보지
I'll try my best.
노력해 볼게
Alright.
좋아요
If you can get him to come,
선생님이 그분을 모셔오시면
we'll play.
저희도 축구 할게요
For real?
진짜?
For real.
- 진짜요
Really.
진짜예요
Alright.
그래
I'll try.
노력해 볼게
Wen Chengye,
원청예
why did you trick me?
왜 날 갖고 놀아?
Let me teach you a lesson.
조언 하나 해 줄게
Don't easily trust others' promises.
남이 해 준다는 약속 함부로 믿지 마
You seem very hostile towards me.
나한테 적대감이 있는 거 같아
I have never offended you, right?
내가 너한테 뭐 잘못한 거 있어?
Is that so?
그래?
Think again.
다시 생각해 봐
Wen Chengye.
원청예
Lay a finger on Fu and you'll see.
푸신수를 건드리기만 해 봐
Seems you've got a new friend.
새 친구가 생겼나 보네
An idiot.
멍청한 놈으로
Who are you calling an idiot?
누구더러 멍청하대?
We just drew with Ning'an.
우린 닝안이랑 비겼어
What's with the "oh"?
할 말 있어?
What does it matter to me?
너희가 어떻게 차든 나랑 무슨 상관이야?
Idiots.
멍청한 놈들
A bunch of idiots.
하나같이 멍청하네
Say that again.
다시 말해 봐
-Come back! -Qin Ao!
- 돌아와 - 친아오
[Director Qian]
[첸 주임]
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
did you find a coach?
감독은 구했어요?
The principal gave the order.
교장 선생님께서 지시하셨어요
You must find a way to form the team
어떻게든 팀을 잘 꾸려야 해요
and achieve some results.
그리고 좋은 성적도 내야 하고요
Good luck. I believe in you.
지켜볼 테니 힘내 봐요
Asking him shouldn't require money, right?
단순히 물어보는 건 괜찮겠지?
[Director Qian]
[첸 주임]
[Contacts]
[연락처 목록]
[New Friends] [I'm Winfred]
[새로운 친구] [저는 윈프레드입니다]
[Please wait]
[잠시만 기다리세요]
[Permission Settings]
[친구 권한]
[Processing]
[지금 처리하고 있습니다]
[Slack Superstar]
[느긋한 초신성]
Mr. Win,
윈 선생님
I would like to take the liberty to ask,
실례지만 여쭤볼 게 있는데요
shouldn't the water leak problem be solved?
누수 문제는 해결해야 하는 거 아닌가요?
I found someone.
사람 구했어요
They will start working tomorrow.
내일 공사할 거예요
By the way, I have another question.
묻는 김에 하나만 더 물어볼게요
Would you be willing...
지난번에
to coach those kids from last time?
그 아이들 데리고 축구 해 줄 수 있어요?
No.
관심 없어요
I knew it.
그럴 줄 알았어
No way.
안 되겠다
For Grandpa,
할아버지를 위해서라도
I must keep this job.
여기에 꼭 남아야 해
What should I do?
어떡하지?
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪
♪ Running towards you ♪
♪ 널 향해 달려가 ♪
♪ I keep moving fearlessly ♪
♪ 두려움 없이 앞으로 나아가 ♪
♪ Walk side by side ♪
♪ 나란히 함께 ♪
♪ Become ourselves ♪
♪ 나 자신이 되어 ♪